Ginni Pinckert

¶ Los Angeles, CA

☐ gcpinckert@gmail.com
☐ gcpinckert.com
☐ gcpinckert

₽ PROFILE

I'm a full-stack software engineer with multiple years of experience in both the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems, as well as experience with various frameworks and AWS. Prior to my career in Software Engineering, I was a Professional Organizer, where my focus was on creating efficient and maintainable systems to help clients better utilize their mental and physical space.

EXPERIENCE

Creator, Software Engineer, *Edamame*

2023 – present

Edamame (get-edamame.com/) 🗹 is an open-source, distributed load-testing framework optimized for real-time collaboration apps. It simulates WebSockets and HTTP traffic for up to 200,000 virtual users.

- Developed a stream processing pipeline (2 million data points per second) for near real-time data visualization, leveraging StatsD aggregation, custom JavaScript and Go programs, and Grafana dashboards.
- Designed a storage strategy enabling data persistence for ephemeral containers (PostgreSQL, Kubernetes, EBS volumes).
- Architected and implemented RESTful database API facilitating app component communication (Node/Express, Docker).
- Contributed to Edamame's CLI, which automates the deployment and removal of AWS cloud infrastructure (EKS cluster, EC2 instances, Kubernetes).
- Served as lead author for a comprehensive case study (get-edamame.com/case-study) 🗵 providing an in-depth analysis of Edamame's problem domain, system design, and engineering decisions.
- Collaborated remotely with an international team of four engineers across three time zones.

Teaching Assistant, Launch School

2021 - 2022

- Conducted over 100 live-coding interview exams and provided actionable feedback to help improve students' performance.
- Evaluated student mastery of programming fundamentals by grading over 200 written assessments.
- Performed detailed code reviews on student projects, addressing bugs, syntax, code conventions, and OOP structure.
- Wrote, created, and produced over 100 video tutorials on topics such as Git/GitHub, Command Line Interface, and JavaScript.

Software Engineer, *Self-employed*

2020 - 2022

Developed open-source applications including projects like:

- Endpoint Bin Tool for collecting, inspecting, and debugging webhooks (DO Droplet, Nginx, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, React)
- Personal Library A book-tracking app with search/filter and authentication (Express, React, MongoDB, Postgres, Docker)
- Itinify An interactive travel itinerary manager, with integrated weather forecasts (Express, Postgres, JavaScript, Handlebars)

Owner, Professional Organizer, Odyssey Organizing

Designed organizing systems and provided productivity consulting services, while managing day-to-day business operations.

⊗ SKILLS

Back End

Node.js, Express, Ruby, Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST

APIs

Cloud

Digital Ocean, AWS, Heroku, Fly.io

JavaScript, React/Redux, Handlebars, HTML, CSS

Other

Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux, Bash, Kubernetes, HTTP, WebSockets, Jest, OOP, Nginx, Postman

EDUCATION

Launch School 2020 - 2022

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum. Read more at launchschool.com/employers 🗷

University of Southern California

2011 - 2013

Completed coursework in Philosophy, Literature, and History